let's briefly talk about Magnetic Tape
which is usually used for backup
purposes or so-called secondary storage
which means that the Magnetic Tape is
not the first device on which you look
for your data you first try to find your
data on the hard drive and only if it's
not there you go to secondary storage
either because the hard drive was lost
and you need to restore a backup or
because this data was not used for a
long long time so it was stored on tapes
and put a away somewhere tapes can have
large capacity and are usually
replaceable meaning you just bring a
reel of tape and you attach to the tape
machine but their access is
fundamentally sequential we need to seek
along the tape until we find the point
we are interested in so tapes are very
good for things like backup restoring
backups and so on when you're writing
things sequentially for a long time or
reading them sequentially for a long
time but tapes are not very good for
example as a virtual memory or something
like that tapes are slowly dying out
mainly because they have a low
production volume because not many
people actually use tape so the cost of
tapes is not dropping as rapidly as the
cost of discs which have much more mass
production so their cost gets cheaper
over time and at this point it's cheaper
to buy an entire hard drive together
with all the motors and the head
assembly and a built-in electronics for
it than to buy some tape and the machine
that will read it so people for example
use USB drives which is pretty much an
entire hard disk just packaged with the
USB interface as a method of backup
storage and so on